孩子们 在2012年的第一天
Kids,on New Year's Day 2012,
马修叔叔去了一趟明尼苏达
Uncle Marshall took a trip to Minnesota
去看望一个他真心想念的人
to see someone he truly missed.
嘿 老爸
Hey, Pop.
不敢相信一年就这么过去了
I can't believe it's been a year.
我认为追忆关于你那美好的回忆
I think the most appropriate way
最合适的方式
to honor your memory today...
就是颓废下来
is to get blasted
看着维京队把熊队
and watch the Vikings make the Bears
虐的不成样
their furry little bitches.
走着 维京人 嘘
Go, Vikes! MOURNER: Shh.
不好意思了
Sorry for your loss.
老爸 我们在大概三个小时的时间里
Which is what we'll be saying to the Bears
该对熊队说些什么呢
in about three hours, right, Pop?
孩子们 狂热地观看维京对阵熊队的比赛
Kids, tailgating at the Vikings-Bears game
是马修叔叔和他爸爸的传统
was a tradition for Uncle Marshall and his dad.
这就是政府如何
That's how the government
掩盖罗斯威尔UFO坠毁事件的
covered up the UFO crash in Roswell:
把切成片的外星人尸体装成罐
by canning the sliced up alien carcasses
称之为猪肉罐头
and calling it Spam.
也就是"外星肉类切片加工"
A.K.A, Sliced Processed Alien Meat
哇
Wow.
世界上还有你不知道的事儿吗 爸
Is there anything you don't know, Dad?
没有
No.
我知道绝大多数的事情
I know most stuff.
对您来说
And in your honor...
三十年的猪肉脂肪 打火机油和奔肌
three decades of pork fat, lighter fluid and Bengay.
额滴神呀 就是这个味儿
Dear God, that's the stuff.
这么多可以让我追寻你的
So much to catch you up on.
昨晚是新年夜
So, last night was New Year's Eve.
这是一个疯狂的故事
That's a crazy story.
你还没告诉你爸爸你已经怀孕了么
So you haven't told your dad that you're pregnant yet?
没呢 不过我为什么要说呢
No. But why should I?
我爸爸从来都不关心我
My dad has never been there for me.
这只会让我再一次的对他失望
This is just another chance for him to let me down.
莉莉 你得告诉他
Lily, you have to tell him.
他在芝加哥的一个桌游大会上
He's at some board game convention in Chicago.
他是你爸爸
He's your dad.
我不知道为什么人们不明白
I don't see why people aren't getting this.
商店扒手游戏不推崇犯罪
Shoplifter does not promote crime.
这是庆祝这个的
It celebrates it.
不好意思
Excuse me.
谁
Yeah.
嘿 爸爸
Hey, Dad.
我 呃 打电话是想告诉你一件大事
I'm, uh, calling with some pretty big news.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
很好 谢谢
Great. Thanks.
老爸老妈浪漫史
第七季  第十三集
翻译:  Mr.Gao 邵小庚 Roy 安达小充 Henry
后期+统筹: Cathy  校对: 47.4 加菲猪
HIMYM字幕组倾情奉献
祝大家新年快乐
不管怎样 爸爸 泰德和巴尼的新年夜
Anyway, Dad, Ted and Barney's New Year's Eve
开始并不顺利
wasn't off to a great start, either.
嘿 别走 别走 入场费50美元
Hey. Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. It's 50 bucks,
外面排队去
and the line starts out there.
额 我们是常客 噢 这样的话
Uh, we're regulars. Oh, in that case,
外面排队去 入场费50美元
the line starts out there, and it's 50 bucks.
你有什么问题么
You got a problem with that?
孩子们 这就是我们为什么没有继续纠缠下去
Kids, here's why we didn't have a problem with that.
他没戴假发看起来更可怕了
And he was even scarier without the toupee.
没问题 外面小风吹着挺好的
No problem. It's a little drafty.
我们给您带一杯可可热饮
We'll get you a nice hot cocoa.
你看看这个
Check it out.
桑迪里弗斯的新年夜节目
Sandy Rivers' New Year's Eve show.
谢天谢地我不用做
Thank God I don't have to produce
这个屎成冰坨子一般的破节目
this frozen pile of poo.
你怎么没做这个节目
How'd you dodge that bullet?
呃 也许蒂娜 制片人 她就
Well, maybe Tina, the producer, she, uh, picked,
四脚朝天躺着等着桑迪在她身上乱搞的时候
is more talented than I am...
决定选一个更有天赋的人吧
at lying down while Sandy does his business on her.
让这个变态做直播
Does it bother you that this pervert's
不会烦你么 好像你也不在意这个了
on the air, and you're not anymore?
你怀念吗
Do you miss it?
什么 为啥 为啥我要怀念呢
What? Why would... why would I miss it?
不 我宁愿
No. I would rather
在我的公寓里暖和又舒服的待着
be warm and cozy here in denial-- my apartment.
罗宾 我不是心理医生
Robin, I'm no therapist--
等等 是 我是
wait, yes, I am--
但是我对你有个新年祝愿
but I've got a New Year's resolution for you.
回到荧幕上去
Get back on camera.
我的愿望是拍一部"小制作A片" 这样就正好一举两得喽
Mine was going to be "Make a sex tape," So... two birds.
你继续想
Hold that thought.
你好
Hello?
桑迪
Sandy?
蒂娜跟我分了
Tina quit.
我爱的那个女人跟我分了
The woman I love just quit.
爱 她是我的全部 罗宾
Love? She's my everything, Robin.
我的太阳 我的星星 我的氧气
My sun, my stars, my oxygen.
补充一下 她喜欢更快更淫乱
Plus, she likes it fast and dirty,
这就是我桑迪的作风
and that's how Sandy rides.
我需要你尽快过来
I need you here ASAP.
你开玩笑么
Are you kidding me?
马库斯
Marcus?
你丫在这干嘛呢
What the heck are you doing here?
你丫又在这干嘛呢
我今天想来看看爸爸 私下的
I wanted to see Dad today-- in private.
好吧 我有同样的想法
Well, I had the same idea,
我一路从妈妈那开车过来 所以你滚蛋吧
and I drove all the way from Mom's, so get lost.
我是飞过来的 所以你滚蛋吧
I flew here, so you get lost.
呃 我试着跟我们已经逝去的爸爸
Um, I'm trying to have a poignant moment
度过一段感人至深的时光 便便脸
with our departed father, turd face.
好吧 我试着感受爸爸的意志
Well, I'm trying to feel Dad's spirit
轻拂我的灵魂 屁股头
flow through my soul,butt breath.
我伸出双手 到达远方
I'm reaching out to the beyond
触碰爸爸的内心之光 你个丑屁股
to touch Dad's inner light, ass clown.
我听见爸爸的声音 犹如圣歌
I hear Dad's voice like an ethereal song
指引我得到救赎 你个喷粪的傻逼
guiding me toward salvation, douche nozzle.
-爸爸归我  -爸爸归我 正无穷
- Dibs on Dad. - Dibs on Dad times infinity.
嗷 唔
Oh! Ooh.
我就当你根本不存在
I'll just pretend like you're not here.
什么
What?
爸爸 你听见没
Dad, do you hear something?
貌似是某个11岁还在尿床的家伙
Perhaps the high-pitched whine of someone who wet their bed
那娘娘腔的哭嚎声
until they were 11!
是10岁了啦
Ten.
无论如何 爸爸 既然这就只有咱俩
Anyway, Dad, since it's just the two of us...
我告诉你 莉莉和我在新年这天
Lily and I were going to spend New Year's
布置育婴房
unpacking the baby room.
额 亲爱的 这书是怎么回事
Um, sweetie, why is this book in here?
那是谜团团
That's Enigmas of The Mystical.
是讲神奇的
It's all about mysterious
无法解释的各种现象
and unexplained phenomena.
你不记得八十年代那个电视广告了么
Don't you remember the TV commercials from the '80s?
1983年6月17日
June 17th, 1983.
亚利桑那州 坦佩
Tempe, Arizona.
一个妇女做了一个鸡肉三明治
A woman makes a chicken salad sandwich.
鸡肉三明治
EERIE WHISPERING: Chicken salad sandwich.
而在横跨了半个国家的密歇根
Halfway across the country in Michigan,
她的女儿心念所使般做了
her daughter is compelled to make
一个几乎一模一样的三明治
almost exactly the same sandwich.
诡异的低语声:金枪鱼沙拉
EERIE WHISPERING: Tuna salad.
这是巧合么
Coincidence?
还是一个神秘的谜团团！
Or an enigma of the mystical!
啊 那些谜什么的对我来说总是有点薄
Yeah, those enigmas always seemed a bit thin to me.
薄? 莉莉 这可是200页
Thin? Lily, this is 200 pages
详细讲述了大脚怪啊 幽灵啊
of detailed accounts about Bigfoot, ghosts,
还有外星人把人类从被窝里绑架走 来探测他们
aliens abducting people from their beds and probing them.
我决定了 我给咱宝宝读这个吧
I'm going to read it to Baby Eriksen
就当睡前小故事
at night-night.
你真打算在睡前
You really want to read our kid
给咱宝宝读怪物的故事么
bedtime stories about monsters?
第一 我不会用'怪物'这个术语
First of all, I wouldn't use the "M" Word.
除非怪物们自我介绍来着
Only they can call themselves that.
第二 你真决定
And secondly, are you really saying
把我们的宝宝教成个无神论者么
you don't want to raise our child as a believer?
我可不想给宝宝洗脑
I don't want to brainwash our child
让它相信些没证据的东西
to believe in something with no proof.
这跟证据神马的没关系 这是关乎信仰的
It's not about proof; it's about faith.
信仰 赋予生活形态与意义
Faith is what gives life shape and meaning.
我是说 如果没有雪人和矮妖
I mean, if there aren't yetis or leprechauns,
早上起床还有什么意义呢
what's the point of even getting up in the morning?
我不晓得
I don't know.
可能是老婆 未出世的孩儿 还有拉场痛快的粑粑
Wife, unborn child, drop a deuce?
莉莉 你不相信世上有比我们更强大的东西
Lily, don't you think it's a bit narcissistic
这不是有点自恋么
not to allow for something bigger than us out there?
你不觉得 有些东西 他们的美丽 力量和威严
Something whose beauty and power
会让我们森森的颤抖么
and majesty humbles us?
-比如上帝  -比如狼人
-God? -Werewolves.
在我们倒数2012的时候
So, as the countdown to 212 continues,
我要给美利坚一个紧急警告
a quick warning, America:
蒂娜-亨德森是个没有灵魂的婊子
Tina Henderson is a soulless bitch
她会无情的践踏你的心
who will stomp on your heart.
蒂娜 你快回来
I need you back, Tina.
我爱你
I love you.
好吧 要是这样就叫坏的不能再坏了 我看我们还不错呢
Well, if that's as bad as it gets, we might be okay.
厕厕时间
Bathroom break.
哦 绝了
Oh, good.
现场直播了
It's on the Jumbotron.
好了
Oh, finally.
每人一百块
Yeah, that'll be 100 bucks each.
啥? 你说五十来着
What? You said 50.
那是淡季价格
That was before the place got crowded.
知道不 现在是新年啦
Okay? It's New Year's Eve.
人山人海 东西乱碎
People get rowdy and break stuff.
这样的掩护会保护咱们
The cover protects us.
另外 给你们些节日帽
Plus, you get these festive hats.
额外加15块钱
For an additional 15 bucks.
这是湿的
They're wet.
干爽的要20块哦亲
Dry ones are 20.
够了
That's it.
别费心了 各位
Don't bother, everybody.
麦克莱伦简直是明抢
MacLaren's is a rip-off!
大家最好
You'd all be better off
上楼去我那喝酒去
coming upstairs to my place for a beer.
嘿伙计 说真的么
Hey, dude. You serious?
泰德 你还记得几年前不
Ted, do you remember a couple yea ago,
那时我们有个宏伟的志向
we had the best idea of a time?
我们应该买个酒吧
We should buy a bar.
必须的 我们应该买个酒吧
Of course! We could buy a bar!
啥名字呢
The name of our bar?
你猜
Puzzles.
别人就会问了"为啥叫你猜?"
People will be like, "Why is it called Puzzles?"
我们就说"你猜"
That's the puzzle.
我们的酒吧 价格低廉
A bar where no one's overcharged,
互相尊重 充满和谐
where everyone feels valued and respected.
我们的酒吧...
A bar...
美女遍地 任人宰割
where we get chicks drunk and bang them.
今晚你猜就开张啦！
We're opening Puzzles tonight.
今晚我们绝对要开张！
Of course we're opening Puzzles tonight!
你不问问它为啥叫你猜么
Aren't you going to ask us why it's called Puzzles?
不鸟
Nope.
成
Okay.
好 直播倒计时30秒
Okay, we're back live in 30 seconds.
桑迪死哪儿去了 不知道啊
- Where's Sandy?  - I don't know.
那么咱们看看他是否还戴着麦
Uht's see if he's still wearing his mic.
的哥 带我去蒂娜家
Taxi, take me to Tina's house.
67西街50号
50 West 67th.
先森 这里是一家沙拉三明治小店
Sir, this is a falafel stand,
而且你坐在了一堆豆沙上
and you're sitting in the hummu
这样吧
Okay.
在姐回来前放一下今年逝世人物大盘点的剪辑
Run the montage of people who died this year until I get back.
叫一下桑迪
And add Sandy,
等我找着他 看我不宰了他
because when I find him, I'm going to kill him.
-不管怎么说 老爸   -别再独占老爸一人了
- Anyway, Dad...   - Stop hogging Dad already.
-我也有东西要告诉他 -你要说啥呢
- I've got stuff to tell him, too. - Like what?
说你现在还啃着老 当无业游民
You're still living with Mom, and you have no job.
败给你了
Go ahead.
好 不管怎样
So, anyway...
1972年 7月8号
July 8, 1972 .
怀俄明州 夏延河
Cheyenne, Wyoming.
一个猎人发现他面前有一个毛茸茸的东西
A hunter spots a hairy form in the fore.
大脚怪
Bigfoot.
他的故事被驳回
His story is dismissed
因为 说实话他喝多了
because, to be honest, he'd been drinking
而且有精神病史
and had a history of mental problems.
但这真是一个骗局吗
But was it a hoax?
或者这是一个谜…
Or was it an enigma of the...
这是个穿着猩猩cosplay的二逼青年
It was an idiot in a gorilla suit.
奇迹 猩猩装
Enigma. Gorilla suit.
谜题啊 猩猩装而已
Enigma! Gorilla suit!
马修 马可斯
Marshall? Marcus?
你们在这里干神马
What are you guys doing here?
跟老爸单独相处一会儿
Having a private moment with Dad.
才不是 是我要和老爸单独呆一会儿
No, I'm having a private moment with Dad.
都散了 我才可以和老爸有一点时间独处
维京队 达阵了
Touchdown, Vikings!
洒家这辈子值了
Boom! Yeah!
算了 老爸
Anyway, Dad,
既然现在还是我们的二人世界
since it's still just the two of us,
我接着说
I'll go on.
我一直想象你猜酒吧应该是个无数来自扭腰客的
I've always envisioned Puzzles as a literary salon,
文艺青年们慕名而来的文化沙龙
where Gotham's intelligentsia hold court
谈论艺术 哲学 还有文学
on art, philosophy and literature.
可以的
Great.
而且当你支开那些宅腐肥妞时
And while you're distracting the nerds and fatties,
我将在这个贵宾房一本满足了
I'll be in the VIP room getting it in.
唔 那个 哥们 我不知道
Uh, yeah, dude, I don't know
你从哪里搞来了绒索栏 可你总不能
where you got a velvet rope, but you can't
在我的房间里和陌生人翻云覆雨吧
use my room for anonymous sex.
我有点洁癖的啦
I'm kind of a neat freak that way.
嘿 筒子们 我有个好主意
Hey, guys, I have an idea for Puzzles.
如果.....这样呢
What if... What?
你猜是只有我们两人才…
Puzzle is kind of a shared envision
哦 好吧 我懂得
Oh. Okay. I understand.
不过我们看好你的干劲啊
But he we like your energy.
要不你就做我们的首席酒保吧
How would you like to be our star bartender.
我一直就想要当个酒保了
I've always wanted to be a bartender.
这就像心理咨询师一样
It's just like being a therapist.
你聆听别人的问题 假装很关心
You listen to people's problems, pretend to care,
但你就可以敞开喝了
but you can drink openly,
不用掖掖藏藏的把酒放在咖啡杯里喝
instead of having to hide your booze in a coffee mug.
不错 对了 听听看
Great. Oh, check it out.
我们为你猜吧搞了首主题曲
We worked out a theme song for Puzzles.
而我扛着100磅的小酒桶
While I was carrying 100-pound kegs
走4段楼梯 爽
up four flights of stairs? Awesome.
如果你来你猜酒吧
Puzzles is a place where people go
这里就是你的家
To feel like they belong
妹纸只要一醉我就啪啪啪 我们不会这样的 哥们儿
Gonna take advantage of dumb drunk girls No, we're not. - Bro
这是不对的啊
That would be a place
风趣智慧在这里开花
where wit and wisdom bloom
泰德房间摘掉你的花
place to bang chicks in Ted's room
不可能发生 我们得谈谈
Not gonna happen.  We'll talk about it.
你猜吧 大家是一家
At Puzzles, we all fit together
酒保仅此一位
And I'm the bartender!
我去多搬点酒桶
I'll go get the other kegs.
这才是好主意
Probably a good idea.
我们得和声一下
We got to work out some harmonies.
我在这里啦 不 你其实在下面啊
And I'm right here No, you actually down here
不好意思啊 这个电视机
Excuse me, sir? About the TVs,
我们现在在下葬我的姨妈
we in the middle burying my aunt, so...
不用 我只是想来看一下比分如何
No, I just want to check out the score.
事实上 我尽量想和
Actually, I'm trying to have
我的老爸单独呆一会儿
a private moment with my dad, so...
哦
Oh.
只是我之前是和我的姨妈一起
It's just that I used to goto Vikes's
去看维京队的比赛 愿她安息
with my aunt; may she rest in peace.
好了 言归正传
Anyway, so back to my story.
她也喜欢汉堡
She also loved burgers.
现在 我接着说
So now, back to my story.
面包烤一烤的话劳拉姨妈会很欣慰的
Aunt Laura sure loved a toasted bun.
蒂娜 桑迪一定要在你那里啊
Tina, please tell me Sandy's here.
别担心 他在这里呢
Don't worry, he's here.
我们又回来了 一起回来的
And we're back... together!
他说他爱我 而且他很抱歉
He told me he loves me, he's sorry,
他说我是他的唯一
and I'm the only girl for him.
那么 既然我们都在一起了
You know, since we're all here,
而且我们又那么淫荡
and we're all horny...
我不知道哪里出错了
I don't know what went wrong.
唔 你提出要玩双飞是不对的
Well, proposing the three-way was bad,
而且我们都不在就开搞是更坏的
starting without us was worse,
在走廊里就完事了你就万劫不复了
finishing in the hallway was the nail in the coffin.
停 别喝了
No! Stop drinking!
我得把你揪回去直播
I gotta get you back on air!
我是光棍待脱光
But I'm single and ready to mingle!
哟 小妞
Hello, there.
哦 那个推特把一家
Oh, the Twitter-verse blowing up about
叫做你猜的全新的公寓主题酒吧吹爆了
a new apartment-themed bar called Puzzles.
为什么叫你猜呢
Why is it called Puzzles?
你猜
That's the puzzle!
总之 这间贵宾室最多能容下
Anyway, this VIP room has a maximum occupancy
两个人 包括我 所以一个
of two people including me, so eeny...
你们其他人可以走了
and the rest of you may go.
说起来很有趣 但好像每次
It's funny, but it seems each time
我读詹姆斯 乔伊斯的《尤利西斯》
I read James Joyce's Ulysses,
它都是一本不同的书
it's a different book,
要讨论的问题是 是书变了
begging the question: Has the book changed...
还是我变了
or have I?
够了 人们开始变得吵闹 喝醉 还打碎东西
Okay, people are getting rowdy and drunk and breaking things.
这违反了你让我背熟的
I know this goes against the Puzzles mission statement
你猜责任声明 但我们必须抬高酒价了
you made me memorize, but we gotta raise our drink prices.
好吧 只抬一点 这样就没人注意到了
All right, just a little bit so no one will notice.
嘭
Boo!
我猜太逊了
Poodles sucks!
这就是那晚彻底毁掉的时候
And that's when the night turned to absolute crap.
在你猜 我们都很愉快
At Puzzles, we all fit together
所以你猜有了一个保镖
And so Puzzles got a bouncer,
好了 知道该怎么样吗 你们
All right, you know what, you guys?
不不不不不不 你说的是按
No. No, no, no, no, no, you said double
麦克莱伦的两倍给我钱
what MacLaren's was paying me.
为什么没人戴我拿来的帽子
And why isn't anyone wearing the hats I brought up?!
1982年
"November 14th...
11月14日
"1982.
佛罗里达的大沼泽地国家公园
"Everglades National Park, Florida.
5个谜一样的的亮光在空中飞舞
"Five mysterious lights dance in the night sky.
一道光线射下 升起了一个公园护林员
"A ray shoots down, lifting the park ranger,
公平的说 他正经历一场很糟糕的离婚
"Who, to be fair, was going through a bad divorce
他还喜欢通过撒谎来吸引人们的注意
and had a habit of lying to get attention."
我恨这份工作 桑迪
I hate this job, Sandy!
我投身新闻事业是为了有所改变
I went into journalism to make a difference,
但你让这变得不可能
but you have made that impossible.
你知道吗 老实说 我这几个月过的
You know, to be honest, it hasn't been
一直不顺 我犯了不少错误
an easy couple months for me. I've made mistakes.
我感到孤独 我要让那些我甚至都不知道我有的
I've felt alone. I had to let go of dreams
梦想离我而去
I didn't even know I had.
所以你给我听好
So here's the deal:
你要继续直播
You're gonna get back on air
把我们倒数到更好的一年
and count us into a better year,
因为我不能再呆在2011了 你听到了吗
because I just can't do 2011 anymore. You with me?
他根本没听 是不是
He's not with me, is he?
总之 爸爸 我当时在哪
Anyway, Dad, where was I?
知道吗 好 滚出去
You know what? Fine, get out of here!
我们不需要你们
We don't need ya!
为什么没人喜欢这些帽子
And why doesn't anybody like these hats?
我做的这些帽子
I made these hats.
因为它们是湿的 道格
It's because they' wet, Doug.
他们为什么都湿了
Why are they all wet?!
那些是我们最后的客人吗
Were those our last customers?
我去看看卫生间
Let me go check the bathroom.
你一定是护送服务的
You must be from the escort service.
本来设想的是高中摔跤比赛
The scenario is high school wrestling match.
你好
Hello?
听听这个 我把桑迪 里弗斯弄丢了
So get this: I lost Sandy Rivers.
有趣的是你应该早说
Funny you should mention that.
马上就要午夜了
It's almost midnight!
我该怎么做 自己上直播
What am I gonna do, go on the air myself?
听着 等一下 好极了 就这么干
Listen... Wait. Yeah, do that!
不 实际上我不能
No, I-I can't actually.
不 你能 这就是你真正想要的也是你应得的
Yes, you can. It's what you really want and you deserve it.
凯文 事情不是那么运作的
Kevin, that's not how it works.
听上去那是你唯一的选择
Sounds like that's your only choice.
纽约是个大城市
New York's a big city.
桑迪 里弗斯可能在任何地方
Sandy Rivers could be anywhere.
预备 开摔
And... wrestle!
嘿
Hey.
对不起 宝贝
I'm sorry, baby.
我只是 我希望我们的孩子
I just... I want our kid
相信宇宙是魔幻的
to believe that the universe is magical.
你知道 就像我爸爸教我的那样
You know, like my dad taught me.
你知道我爸爸教我什么了吗
You know what my dad taught me?
什么也没教 因为他从来不在我身边
Nothing... 'cause he was never there.
1996年6月22日 纽约 布鲁克林
"June 22nd, 1996, Brooklyn, New York.
一个男人错过了他女儿的高中毕业典礼
"A man misses his daughter's high school graduation.
后来 她发现她照顾孩子的钱
"Later, she discovers her babysitting money
被花在了一个叫做
"Has been spent on a board game called
谁偷了看孩子的钱的桌游
Who Stole The Babysitting Money?"
他始终看不出来这里面的讽刺
He never saw the irony in that.
2011年12月31日
"December 31st, 2011.
一个女人给他的爸爸打电话告诉他她怀孕了
"A woman calls her father to tell him she's pregnant.
说 好极了 谢谢 然后挂掉了他的电话
says, 'Great. Thanks,' and hangs up on her."
在促使她给他打电话后
And after pushing her to call him,
在他丈夫的嘴里发现了一只大脚怪
a Big Foot is discovered in her husband's mouth.
我很高兴你相信这些 宝贝
I'm glad you're a believer, baby,
但我永远不会相信谜团团
but I'm never gonna believe in an "Enigma of the mystical"
除非我亲眼看到
unless I see it with my own eyes.
因为实际上
Because the truth is,
我爸爸从不教我相信任何事 除了我自己
my father never taught me believe in anything but myself.
那么 如果有用的话 我也相信你
Well, if it helps at all, I believe in you, too.
那么很有可能我是不存在的
Then there's a pretty good chance I don't exist.
你胆子不小
How dare you?!
哦 天啊
Oh, my God!
这里是罗宾 舍巴斯基 代替桑迪 里弗斯
This is Robin Scherbatsky filling in for Sandy Rivers.
你知道吗 美国
You know, America,
今晚我被人吃了豆腐 踩到了呕吐物
tonight I've been groped, stepped in puke
10分钟以前我都没想到能在全国电视台上出镜
and until 10 minutes ago I had no idea I would be on national television
果然是我认识的罗宾
That's my girl.
不过这就是新年到来的神奇之处
But that's the magic of New Year's.
当时针指向零点午夜的时候
When that clock strikes midnight,
我们就会迎来一个全新的开始
we all get a fresh start.
我虽然不知道大家会如何 但我肯定会有一个好的开始
And I don't know about you, but I could really use one.
这个神奇的时刻就会发生在十
And that magic moment starts in ten...
九
nine...
那夜也变成了罗宾职业路上得一个转折点
That night became a turning point in Robin's career.
不过这个我们以后再说
But we'll get to that.
这些帽子很可爱啊 道格
They're nice hats, Doug.
他们虽然是湿的不过好看啊
They're wet but they're nice.
三 二 一
...three, two, one.
这就是新年前夜的一段故事
And that's the story of New Year's Eve.
我最近一直在思考 你知道么
You know, I've been thinking
我跟莉莉的关系非常紧张的原因是
that the reason I got so intense with Lily
有关于谜团团这本书 那个
about Enigmas of the Mystical is that, well...
你能递给我那罐酸菜么
Could you pass the pickles?
随着你的离开 我感觉谜团团并没有那么的神秘了
...with you gone, I feel the mystical a little less.
你能递给我那包薯片么
Can you hand me the chips?
而且有时候我我觉得我想起您的时候更少了
Sometimes I feel you a little less.
这就是为什么今天那么的重要
That's why today was so important because I just...
我需要跟
I needed to...
你是刚刚用我爸的墓碑开了你的瓶酒么
Did you just open a beer on my father's headstone?
其实 这支是苹果酒(酒精低于10%)
Actually, it's a hard cider.
正当他感觉到要失控的时候
And just as he was about to lose it...
嘿 马文 你能递给我个汉堡么
Hey, Marvin, can you pass me a burger?
噢 不是马文 是马修
Hey, not Marvin. Marshall.
不好意思 只是 只是你跟你老爸非常的像
Sorry, it's just, you're so much like your pop.
你们的马修叔叔又想到
Your Uncle Marshall thought back
那些在车后挡板与父亲一起的故事
to all those tailgates with his father.
嘿 你介意我拿一个走么
Hey, mind if I grab one?
-拿的越多我越高兴   -那敢情好
-The more the merrier!   -All right.
时间会慢慢愈合我们的伤口
The time has come to heal our wounds
这个时刻就要来临 即将来临
The time has come, it's coming soon...
他意识到他对于自己所认为的私人空间看得太重了
And he realized that maybe private moments are overrated.
我告诉你
You know what?
你拿得越多越好
The more the merrier.
嘿 大伙
Hey, guys.
时间会抚平这个伤口
The time has come to heal the wounds.
新年快乐
Happy New Year.
二零一二年元月一号 东梅多 纽约
January 1st, 2012, East Meadow, New York.
一个女人发现了更神秘的事情在她的自家门口
A woman answers her door to find something more enigmatic
甚至比大脚怪和尼斯湖水怪更加神秘的事情
and mysterious than Bigfoot or the Loch Ness Monster.
爸
Dad?
嘿
Hey.
你不是在芝加哥么
I thought you were in Chicago.
我之前是在
I was.
知道了 谢谢通知
Great. Thanks.
我女儿怀孕啦
My daughter's having a baby!
你开了一整夜过来的么
Did you drive all night?
恩
Yeah.
呵呵 泰迪熊跟我轮换开车过来的
Well, Teddy and I split the drive.
这伙计就在车上就像个疯子
This guy's a maniac behind the wheel.
恭喜了 我的小公主
Congrats, Princess.
新年快乐 爸
Happy New Year, Dad.
HIMYM字幕组倾情奉献